const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the mode of action of alpha-2 agonists?","answers":[{"option":"Decreases aqueous production and increases uveoscleral outflow","bool":true},{"option":"Decreases trabecular outflow","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases aqueous production","bool":false},{"option":"Constriction of pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Increases aqueous outflow","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"According to WHO, blindness is defined as visual acuity of or less than which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Counting fingers only","bool":false},{"option":"No perception of light","bool":false},{"option":"6/60","bool":false},{"option":"6/18","bool":false},{"option":"3/60","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"What is the mechanism of action of a topical carbonic anhydrase inhibitor on the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Increases aqueous outflow","bool":false},{"option":"Contracts pupillary sphincter muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Blocks the trabecular meshwork","bool":false},{"option":"Contracts ciliary muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases aqueous secretion","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Atropine acts on what receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Muscarinic","bool":true},{"option":"Beta adrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha adrenergic","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotinic","bool":false},{"option":"Opioid","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following lasers is used for pan-retinal photocoagulation in patients with diabetic retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Argon laser","bool":true},{"option":"Nd YAG laser","bool":false},{"option":"Femtosecond laser","bool":false},{"option":"Excimer laser","bool":false},{"option":"Holmium laser","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most prevalent cause of blindness?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal opacities","bool":false},{"option":"Aphakia","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following systemic diseases is closely associated with episcleritis?","answers":[{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Crohns disease","bool":false},{"option":"Ankylosing spondylitis","bool":false},{"option":"Behcet disease","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"LASIK can correct astigmatism up to how many diopters?","answers":[{"option":"5 D","bool":true},{"option":"12 D","bool":false},{"option":"4 D","bool":false},{"option":"8 D","bool":false},{"option":"3 D","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which wall of the orbit is the strongest?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral","bool":true},{"option":"Base","bool":false},{"option":"Floor","bool":false},{"option":"Roof","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following bones make the roof of the orbit?","answers":[{"option":"The greater wing of sphenoid only","bool":false},{"option":"The zygomatic bone and greater wing of the sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"The maxilla, palatine and zygomatic bones","bool":false},{"option":"The frontal bone and the lesser wing of the sphenoid","bool":true},{"option":"The ethmoid and maxilla","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"At what distance should visual acuity be tested?","answers":[{"option":"20m","bool":false},{"option":"10m","bool":false},{"option":"12m","bool":false},{"option":"6m","bool":true},{"option":"18m","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"What is the densest opacity of the cornea called?","answers":[{"option":"Ectatic cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Adherent leucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Nebula","bool":false},{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"Leucoma","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Intorsion and extorsion are examples of which of the following movement?","answers":[{"option":"Rotatory","bool":false},{"option":"Version","bool":false},{"option":"Duction","bool":true},{"option":"Accommodative","bool":false},{"option":"Convergence","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of blindness in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is a nonmodifiable risk factor for diabetic retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Dyslipidemia","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic control","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Duration of diabetes","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following statements is true about chalazion?","answers":[{"option":"Acute suppurative infection of the lash follicle and its associated glands","bool":false},{"option":"Acute suppurative infection of Zeis and Moll","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic inflammation of the Meibomian gland","bool":true},{"option":"Acute suppurative infection of the Meibomian gland","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic inflammation of the eyelid margins","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following statements is true about basal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"It arises from nerve sheath","bool":false},{"option":"It is a benign tumor","bool":false},{"option":"It is the least common malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"It is non metastasizing","bool":true},{"option":"It is not locally invasive","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"A 37-year-old patient presents with painful, red swelling at the medial side of the lower eyelid. The regurgitation test is positive and mucopurulent discharge is oozing from the upper punctum. Which of the following structures is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal puncti","bool":false},{"option":"Main lacrimal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal sac","bool":true},{"option":"Conjunctival sac","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory lacrimal glands","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"A 20-year-old female presents with mildly painful red eyes to the eye clinic. She also complains of blurred vision and increased ocular sensitivity to light. Fluorescein corneal staining shows an amoeboid-shaped corneal ulcer. The patient's eyes do not blink or tear when a cotton bud is placed on the cornea. What is the most likely infectious agent?","answers":[{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes zoster virus","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following organisms most commonly causes preseptal cellulitis in children?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Moraxella catarrhalis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Episcleritis is treated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-VEGF","bool":false},{"option":"Topical steroids","bool":true},{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":false},{"option":"Bevacizumab","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"What is the most conspicuous sign of conjunctivitis?","answers":[{"option":"Erythema due to dilatation of the superficial vessels","bool":true},{"option":"Photophobia","bool":false},{"option":"Mucopurulent discharge","bool":false},{"option":"Periocular tenderness upon palpation","bool":false},{"option":"Increased lacrimation and positive regurgitation tests","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the weakest wall of the orbit?","answers":[{"option":"Roof","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Floor","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"What is a fleshy triangular fibrovascular mass encroaching out to the cornea known as?","answers":[{"option":"Pinguecula","bool":false},{"option":"Bowen's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Psuedopterygium","bool":false},{"option":"Symblepharon","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygium","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the correct range for normal intraocular pressure (IOP)?","answers":[{"option":"10-21 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"15-20 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"10-30 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"20-30 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"5-10 mmHg","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following organisms most commonly causes viral conjunctivitis?","answers":[{"option":"Measles virus","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes Simplex","bool":false},{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":true},{"option":"Picornavirus","bool":false},{"option":"Molluscum contagiosum","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"What is the first sign that the parents observe in a child with congenital glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Pain","bool":false},{"option":"Optic disc cupping","bool":false},{"option":"Photophobia","bool":false},{"option":"Redness","bool":false},{"option":"Epiphora","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is not a differential diagnosis of leukocoria?","answers":[{"option":"Coat's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital glaucoma","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Retrolental fibroplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most common surgical method for treating myopia?","answers":[{"option":"Clear lens extraction","bool":false},{"option":"Laser Epithelial Keratomileusis (LASEK)","bool":false},{"option":"Photorefractive Keratectomy (PRK)","bool":false},{"option":"Laser in Situ Keratomileusis (LASIK)","bool":true},{"option":"Radical Keratotomy (RK)","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following causes of clinical blindness has decreased in the last 20 years?","answers":[{"option":"Refractive errors","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Infections","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most common treatment for refractive errors?","answers":[{"option":"LASIK","bool":false},{"option":"Contact lenses","bool":false},{"option":"All of them","bool":false},{"option":"Glasses","bool":true},{"option":"Surgery","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following conditions is associated with Eales disease?","answers":[{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is a common presentation of allergic conjunctivitis?","answers":[{"option":"White, stringy mucus discharge","bool":false},{"option":"Itching","bool":true},{"option":"Photophobia","bool":false},{"option":"Increase blinking","bool":false},{"option":"Foreign body sensation","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment for viral conjunctivitis?","answers":[{"option":"Topical steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Antivirals","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Irrigation of the eye","bool":false},{"option":"Symptomatic and supportive","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"A 14-year-old boy presents to the clinic with the complaint of blurred vision and headaches for 3 months. In school, he has difficulty reading the blackboard from afar but is able to read his textbooks without difficulty. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Third cranial nerve palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":false},{"option":"Emmetropia","bool":false},{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of optic neuritis?","answers":[{"option":"Post immunization","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Contagious infection from orbit","bool":false},{"option":"Syphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Demyelinating disorder","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most dangerous foreign body for the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Copper","bool":false},{"option":"Iron","bool":true},{"option":"Coal","bool":false},{"option":"Plastic","bool":false},{"option":"Glass","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following conditions results in purulent discharge from the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Vernal conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Allergic inflammation of conjunctiva","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal infection","bool":false},{"option":"Severe acute bacterial conjunctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute viral conjunctivitis","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"A 2-day-old neonate presents with frank purulent conjunctival discharge. On examination, the eyelids are red and edematous.  What is the most likely causative organism of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"A 35-year-old man comes to the physician with purulent discharge from eyes, edematous eyelids, and preauricular lymphadenopathy. Which of the following is the most likely cause of his complaints?","answers":[{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes Simplex","bool":false},{"option":"Trachoma","bool":false},{"option":"Allergic","bool":false},{"option":"Gonococcal","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the earliest sign seen in diabetic retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Hard exudates","bool":false},{"option":"Cotton wool spots","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal edema","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal haemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Microaneurysms","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following systemic antibiotics is used as the treatment of choice for trachoma?","answers":[{"option":"Sulphacetamide","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":true},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is true regarding normal-tension glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Reduction of IOP is not useful","bool":false},{"option":"Visual field loss is not progressive","bool":false},{"option":"No optic disc cupping is seen","bool":false},{"option":"It is associated with obstructive sleep apnea","bool":true},{"option":"IOP greater than 21 mm Hg","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"If the primary open-angle glaucoma does not resolve with medical treatment. What will be the best form of management?","answers":[{"option":"Iridectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Laser therapy","bool":true},{"option":"High dose steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Trabeculectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Iridotomy","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following orbital wall is most likely to be affected in a blow-out fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of the orbit","bool":true},{"option":"Roof","bool":false},{"option":"Inferolateral wall","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Osmotic agents like mannitol are used to treat which type of glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Acute open angle glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Acute angle closure glaucoma","bool":true},{"option":"Intermediate angle closure glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoexfoliative glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Normal tension glaucoma","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following diseases is associated with post-trabecular glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Riley Day syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Down's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Galactosaemia","bool":false},{"option":"Goodpasture syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Sturge-Weber syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"What is the treatment of choice for progressive pterygium encroaching the visual axis of the cornea?","answers":[{"option":"Surgical excision","bool":true},{"option":"Steroid drops","bool":false},{"option":"Lubricating drops","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotic drops","bool":false},{"option":"Observation","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of acquired cataracts?","answers":[{"option":"Ocular disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Aging","bool":true},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Drugs","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following does not cause pain in corneal ulcers?","answers":[{"option":"Exposure of corneal nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulation of corneal nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Spasm of ciliary body","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulation of vasculature","bool":true},{"option":"Raised intraocular pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following effects is used in photocoagulation?","answers":[{"option":"Photochemical effect","bool":false},{"option":"Thermal effect","bool":true},{"option":"Electrochemical effect","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanical effect","bool":false},{"option":"Ionizing effect","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following is used to stain the bed of corneal ulcers?","answers":[{"option":"All of them","bool":false},{"option":"Rose bengal","bool":false},{"option":"Fluorescein","bool":true},{"option":"Lissamine green","bool":false},{"option":"Trypan Blue","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"What is the total number of monocular movements?","answers":[{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"8","bool":false},{"option":"6","bool":true},{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"10","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Lesion at which site leads to bitemporal hemianopia?","answers":[{"option":"Optic radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Optic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Visual cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Optic chiasm","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Lesion in which of the following cranial nerves causes diplopia when the patient tries to look towards the right side?","answers":[{"option":"Right abducens nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Left oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right  oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left abducens nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which two processes take place when a person sees a near object?","answers":[{"option":"Light reflex and divergence","bool":false},{"option":"Light reflex and accommodation","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation and convergence","bool":true},{"option":"Accommodation and divergence","bool":false},{"option":"Divergence and convergence","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following statements is true about blepharitis?","answers":[{"option":"Madarosis is a complication of blepharitis","bool":true},{"option":"All of them","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous blepharitis is caused by S. epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous blepharitis can cause ulcers","bool":false},{"option":"Ulcerative is also called seborrheic","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Within how many hours donor tissue should be removed after death in keratoplasty?","answers":[{"option":"10 hours","bool":false},{"option":"1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"48 hours","bool":false},{"option":"40 hours","bool":false},{"option":"24 hours","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"A 6-year-old boy fell from the ladder. Imaging reveals an orbital fracture. Which of the following is most likely fractured in an orbital trauma?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior wall","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital roof","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"What is the age of presentation of accommodative esotropia?","answers":[{"option":"7-10 years","bool":false},{"option":"6-12 months","bool":false},{"option":"3-5 years","bool":false},{"option":"18-36 months","bool":true},{"option":"7-9 years","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"Which of the following statements is not correct regarding nuclear sclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"It is a normal condensation process","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs after middle age","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms include monocular diplopia","bool":false},{"option":"Results in myopic shift","bool":false},{"option":"Results in hypermetropic shift","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"A yellow-white bulbar mass on the conjunctiva is what condition?","answers":[{"option":"Phlyctenulosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pinguecula","bool":true},{"option":"Xerophthalmia","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygium","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudopterygium","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/eye/2018","question":"In which part of the eye does the maximum refraction take place?","answers":[{"option":"Cornea","bool":true},{"option":"Vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Crystalline lens","bool":false},{"option":"Aqueous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Retina","bool":false}]}]
export default arr